

Min Hein Kyaw

Part-time English Instructor

🗷 minheiin.kyaw@gmail.com 🧳 +959452701942 🛮 😭 Yangon, Myanmar

https://www.linkedin.com/in/min-hein-kyaw/

Professional Summary

An experienced English teacher with a band score of **7.5** in IELTS and 2 years of classroom experiment. Taught both primary and secondary students using the **Singapore curriculum** and **IGCSE English** frameworks emphasizing strong grammar foundations, critical reading, structured writing, and fluent speaking.

Work Experience

English Teacher Oct 2023 - Present

Hallway International School

- Taught IGCSE O level students how to analyze the given text and answer the respective questions
- Taught different types of writing (letter, magazine article, journal, formal article)
- Taught Secondary students how to write academic essays, how to understand comprehensions and answer the questions perfectly, paraphrasing the summaries perfectly and how to use grammar properly
- · Taught primary students related to grammar, vocabulary and writing aligned by Singaporean Curriculum

IGCSE ICT and CS instructor

Oct 2023 - Present

- · Taught IGCSE O level students how to use office tools and understanding digital literacy
- Taught complex terms and ideas using simple English
- · Taught critical thinking and analytical skills by solving programming problems and algorithms and flowcharts

Computer Science Instructor

Latwae Education

- Trained students annually in competitive programming and algorithm design using code.org, scratch and Codementum
- Taught first prize winning students in Scratch and STEM Olympiad competition

Education

Bachelor of Engineering (Information Technology)

Dec 2017 - Present

West Yangon Technological University

• **Key Coursework:** Database Management Systems, Data Structures and Algorithms, Software Engineering, Computer Networks, Web Development, Programming Languages (Java, PHP, C++), Operating Systems.

Certifications

Teaching English as a Foreign Language Course

Teacher Record

https://teacherrecord.com/checking/TR1820639954

IELTS Band Score of 7.5

British Council

1719768600000

https://drive.google.com/file/d/10YBvBlhj3ExKhlErRGwsPo2Hx-_UMOuF/view?usp=sharing

Teaching Knowledge Test (TKT)

Cambridge English

https://drive.google.com/file/d/12iRY_DDGSKloy209cOfAQLR5P_vk7TBt/view?usp=sharing

Achievements

- Outstanding Academic Achievement Award of Bridge Education Program by ISP
- IELTS high score achiever

Burmese English